Guide to the Leroy E. Burney Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES, 1931-(1960-1978); Series I; 9' (21 boxes)
  - Other Activities
    - National Commission for the Study of Nursing and Nursing Education
      - Miscellaneous material, 1971-1972, undated (Box 12, Folder 178)
      - Directories, 1971-1973 (Box 12, Folder 179)
      - Minutes of Board of Commissioners, 1971-1973 (Box 12, Folder 180)
      - Monthly memoranda, 1972 January-Oct, December (Box 12, Folder 181)
      - Progress report, "From Abstract into Action", 1972 March (Box 12, Folder 182)
      - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 183)
      - Memoranda and summary re: Invitational Conference on Issues in Licensed Practical Nursing, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 184)
      - Press releases, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 185)
      - Summary of target and other state activities, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 186)
      - Memoranda, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 187)
      - Reference material re: National Joint Practice Commission, 1972-1973, undated (Box 12, Folder 188)
      - Monthly memoranda, 1973 Jan, March-October (Box 12, Folder 189)
      - Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 190)
      - "Plan for the Longitudinal Study of Impact on Health Care Exerted by the NCSNNE" (and preliminary draft), 1976 (Box 12, Folder 191)
      - Charts re: nursing roles and functions, undated (Box 12, Folder 192)
    - National Council for International Health
      - Correspondence, minutes and background material, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 193)
      - Correspondence, minutes and background material, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 194)
      - Correspondence, minutes and background material, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 195-196)
      - Correspondence and background material, 1976-1977 (Box 13, Folder 197)
      - Report, "Communicating Health Efforts and Research/A Feasibility Study for an Information Exchange System in International Health", 1975 October 6 (Box 13, Folder 198)
      - Agenda books, 1972 February 1-2, 1972 April 21, 1972 August 1, 1972 December 7 (Box 13, Folder 199-202)
      - Agenda books, 1973 February 15, 1973 April 24, 27, 1973 September 12, 1973 December 13, 1974 March 1, 1974 April 29, 1974 December 9 (Box 14, Folder 203-209)
      - Agenda books, 1975 May 5, 1975 June 20, 1975 October 19, 1975 December 5, 1976 February 19, 1976 April 13 (Box 15, Folder 210-215)
      - Correspondence and press release, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 216)
      - Correspondence, minutes and program, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 217)
      - Correspondence and minutes, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 218-219)
      - Correspondence, minutes and leaflets, 1971-1973 (Box 16, Folder 220-222)
      - Correspondence, leaflets and miscellaneous material, 1974-1975 (Box 16, Folder 223)
      - Publications
        - "Alternatives for Organizing Personal Health Care Delivery", 1970 (Box 16, Folder 224)
        - "The Changing Role of the Public and Private Sectors in Health Care" (report of the 1973 National Health Forum), 1973 March 20-21 (Box 17, Folder 225)
        - "Continuity and Change" (1968 annual report), Circa 1968 December (Box 17, Folder 226)
        - "Health Manpower Activities", 1971 (Box 17, Folder 227)
        - "Health Manpower: Adapting in the Seventies" (report of the 1971 National Health Forum), 1971 March 15-17 (Box 17, Folder 228)
        - "Licensure Accreditation and Certification", 1971 (Box 17, Folder 229)
        - "The Minority Tapes", 1971 (Box 17, Folder 230)
        - "Task Force Report on the Health Manpower Distribution Project," and "Distribution of Health Manpower/an Annotated Bibliography", 1973 (Box 17, Folder 231)
        - "Viewpoints on State and Local Legislation Regulating Solicitation of Funds from the Public", 1971 (Box 17, Folder 232)
    - National Sanitation Foundation
      - Correspondence, minutes and background material, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 233)
      - Correspondence, minutes and agendas, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 234)
      - Correspondence, minutes and background material, 1971-1972 (Box 18, Folder 235-236)
      - Correspondence and minutes, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 237)
    - President's Committee on Health Education
      - Correspondence, minutes and background, material, 1971 December - 1972 May (Box 18, Folder 238-244)
      - Correspondence, minutes and background material, 1972 June-August (Box 19, Folder 245)
      - Correspondence and background material, 1972 September-1973 (Box 19, Folder 246)
      - Final report, first draft, 1972 June (Box 19, Folder 247)
      - Final report, third draft, 1972 August (Box 19, Folder 248)
      - Final report, fourth draft, 1972 August (Box 19, Folder 249)
      - Final report, draft (Syd Harris), 1972 September (Box 19, Folder 250)
      - Final report, draft (Joy Cauffman), 1972 November (Box 19, Folder 251)
      - Final report, draft, 1972 November (Box 19, Folder 252)
      - Final report, final draft, 1972 December (Box 19, Folder 253)
      - "Message from the President of the United States Relative to Building a National Health Strategy", 1971 February 18 (Box 19, Folder 254)
      - Miscellaneous reports, 1972 February (Box 19, Folder 255)
      - Miscellaneous press releases, leaflet and newsclippings, 1971-1972 (Box 19, Folder 256)
      - Miscellaneous lists, schedules and data, 1971-1972 (Box 19, Folder 257)
    - Temple University
      - Grant application, brochure and correspondence, 1963-1970 (Box 20, Folder 258)
      - Board of Trustees' Committee for Long Range Planning for the Health Sciences Center: "Briefing Documents", 1968 March (Box 20, Folder 259)
    - United Presbyterian Church
      - Board of National Missions: correspondence, minutes and background material, 1969-1970, undated (Box 20, Folder 260)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1969-1972 (Box 20, Folder 261)
  - Reference Files
    - Water Studies, Cattaraugus County Department of Health, 1931 (Box 20, Folder 262)
    - General pampblets and papers, 1938, 1959, 1965-1969 (Box 20, Folder 263)
    - Papers presented at symposia on industrial nursing, philadelphia, 1959-1961 (Box 20, Folder 264)
    - Reprints and papers re: pharmacy, 1966-1972 (Box 20, Folder 265)
    - Reprints and papers re: group health plans, 1967-1970 (Box 20, Folder 266)
    - Reprints and papers re: medical care utilization, 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 267)
    - General Pamphlets and papers, 1970-1972 (Box 21, Folder 268)
    - Reprints and papers re: national health insurance, 1971, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 269)
    - Reprints and papers re: medical care utilization, 1971-1972 (Box 21, Folder 270)
    - Reprints and papers re: group health plans, 1971-1974 (Box 21, Folder 271)
    - General pamphlets and papers, 1973-1976 (Box 21, Folder 272)
- WRITINGS, 1937-1963, undated; Series II; 3' (8 boxes)
  WRITINGS is arranged chronologically. Undated items are filed at the end of the series.
  - "The Control of Syphilis and Gonorrhea," Journal of the Indiana State Medical Association: reprint, 1937 March 1 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - "The Venereal Disease Program in Richmond with Recommendations for Suggested Changes," Virginia Medical Monthly: reprint, 1937 September (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - "Results of Serologic Tests for Syphilis in Non-Syphilitic Persons Inoculated with Malaria," American Journal of Public Health: reprint, 1942 January (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - "Merit System in Public Health," American Journal of Public Health: reprint, 1944 November (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - "An Approach to Better Dental Health and Dental Care," Monthly Bulletin, Indiana State Board of Health: reprint, 1945 October (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - "Concerning the Signing of Death Certificates," Journal of Indiana State Medical Association: reprint, 1945 October (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - "Services Available from Your State Board of Health": speech text, 1945 December 8 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - "Postmortem Examinations," Journal of Indiana State Medical Association: reprint, 1945 December (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - "New Trends and Developments: in Public Health": speech text, 1946 January 28 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - "Legislation Affecting the Indiana State Board of Health": speech text, 1946 March 15 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - "New Branch State Health Department Services Available to Water Works": speech text, 1946 April 2 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - "Legislation Affecting the Indiana State Board of Health," Journal of Indiana State Medical Association: reprint, 1946 May (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - "A Professional Man Looks at Planning": speech text, 1946 August 15 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - "Teamwork in the Eradication of Tuberculosis," Hoosier Health Herald: reprint, 1946 August (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - "Services of New State Health Department Branches," Journal of the American Water Works Association: reprint, 1946 September (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - "The General Practitioner in a Public Health Program," Journal of the Indiana State Medical Association: reprint, 1946 October (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - "Needed Public Health Legislation": speech text, 1946 December 27 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - "Better Health for Better Farm Living": article draft, 1946 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - "Public Health Legislation Enacted by the General Assembly," Journal of the Indiana State Medical Association: reprint, 1947 April (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - "Implications of Recent Public Health Legislation," Hoosier Health Herald: reprint and speech text, 1947 May-June (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - "The Role of the Department of Education and the Department of Health in the Inservice Preparation of Classroom Teachers, School Administrators, School Nurses and School Physicians": speech text and abstract, 1947 October 8 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - "The Hospital Planning and Licensing Programs in Indiana": speech text and abstract, 1947 October 10 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - "Hospital Relations, the Hospital Planning and Licensing Programs in Indiana," American Journal of Public Health: reprint, 1947 December (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - "Relationship Between Official and Voluntary Health Agencies": article draft, 1947 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - "Preservice and Inservice Preparation in Health of School Personnel," American Journal of Public Health: reprint, 1948 January (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - "Making Licensure Democratic": article draft and correspondence, 1948 March 24 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - "Building and Guarding Good Health," Public Welfare in Indiana: reprint, 1948 March (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - "Public Health Education and Community Organization": speech text, 1948 April 16 (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - "The National Health Assembly": speech text, 1948 June 26 (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - "The Development of Local Health Units": speech text, 1948 September 26 (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - "Health Conditions in County Homes," Public Welfare in Indiana: reprint and draft, 1948 (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - "Interest in Full-Time Local Health Departments," Indiana State Medical Journal: article drafts and correspondence, 1948 (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - "The Problem of the Degenerative Diseases": speech text, 1949 January 25 (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - "The Future of Public Health in the United States": speech text, 1949 April 7 (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - "Federal Legislation for National Health": speech text, 1949 May 5 (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - "The Contributions of a Program of State Licensure": speech text, 1949 September 28 (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - "Some Problems in the Recruitment and Training of Public Health Personnel," American Journal of Public Health: reprint and speech draft, 1949 December (Box 22, Folder 37)
  - "What a State Poliomyelitis Planning Committee Accomplishes": speech text, 1950 March 17 (Box 22, Folder 38)
  - "The Health and Economic Significance of Keeping Indiana a Tuberculin Tested Accredited Area": speech text, 1950 March 29 (Box 22, Folder 39)
  - "A Job for All": report text, 1950 April (Box 22, Folder 40)
  - "The Local Board of Health": speech text, 1950 May 4 (Box 22, Folder 41)
  - "The Economic and Public Health Aspect of Animal Diseases": speech text, 1950 August 1 (Box 22, Folder 42)
  - "The Indiana State Board of Health and the Medical Profession": speech text, 1950 September 25 (Box 22, Folder 43)
  - "Where Does the Service of a Health Department to a Community Begin and End?": speech text, 1950 September 28 (Box 22, Folder 44)
  - "Consumers' Health Protection": speech text and drafts, 1950 October 4 (Box 22, Folder 45)
  - "An Investment in Life Conservation": speech text, 1950 (Box 22, Folder 46)
  - "The Indiana Polio Planning Committee," Hospitals: reprint and speech text, 1950-1951 (Box 22, Folder 47)
  - "Indiana's Plan for Health Services in Civil Defense," Journal of the Indiana State Medical Association: reprint, 1951 February (Box 22, Folder 48)
  - "The Role of the Hospital in Civil Defense": speech text, 1951 April 30 (Box 22, Folder 49)
  - "Experiments in Hospital Planning and Licensing": speech text, 1951 May 26 (Box 22, Folder 50)
  - "The Impact of Civil Defense Upon the Medical Profession," Journal of the Indiana State Medical Association: article draft, 1951 June (Box 22, Folder 51)
  - "Liason Relationships in Organized Medicine": speech text and abstract, 1951 October 15 (Box 22, Folder 52)
  - "Cooperative Efforts Between Dairy Plants and the State Board of Health": speech text, 1951 December 4 (Box 22, Folder 53)
  - "Improving Health Care in Private and Public Nursing Homes," Geriatrics: reprint, abstract and correspondence, 1951-1952 (Box 22, Folder 54)
  - "Teaching Home Nursing in Indiana," American Journal of Public Health: reprint, draft and correspondence, 1952 January-October (Box 22, Folder 55)
  - "Industry's Contributions to Health Problems of the Aging": speech text, 1952 July 28 (Box 22, Folder 56)
  - "How Can Voluntary and Official Agencies Cooperate to Achieve Better Patient Care": speech text, 1952 September 14 (Box 22, Folder 57)
  - "Changing Health Picture and Its Challenge to the Health Professional": article drafts and memoranda, 1952 Nov, 1953 February (Box 22, Folder 58)
  - "Livestock Diseases and Human Health": speech text and abstract, 1952 December 1 (Box 22, Folder 59)
  - "Premarital Serology," Journal of the Indiana State Medical Association: text, 1953 Mar, May (Box 22, Folder 60)
  - "The Challenge of population Trends to public Health": speech text and abstract, 1953 April 9 (Box 22, Folder 61)
  - "New Horizons in public Health": speech text, 1953 September 11 (Box 22, Folder 62)
  - Community Organization—An Effective Tool: speech text, 1953 November 10 (Box 22, Folder 63)
  - "Community Organization—An Effective Tool," American Journal of Public Health: reprint, 1954 January (Box 22, Folder 64)
  - "Indiana Health": speech text (summary), 1954 April 14 (Box 22, Folder 65)
  - "New Frontiers, Responsibilities and Opportunities of Public Health": speech text, 1954 May 10 (Box 22, Folder 66)
  - Speeches: bound volume, 1954 July-1956 December (Box 23, Folder 67)
  - "The Citizen's Share in Public Health Programs," The Sight-Saving Review: reprint, 1954 (Box 23, Folder 68)
  - "Lay Evaluation of Environmental Sanitation": outline, correspondence and speech text, 1954 (Box 23, Folder 69)
  - "Progress Creates Problems": speech drafts, Circa 1955 February 9 (Box 23, Folder 70)
  - "The Combined Role of the Physician, Health Department and Hospital in Meeting Community Health Needs": speech text, 1955 May 4 (Box 23, Folder 71)
  - "Preserving the Health of the Nation's Older People". speech text, 1956 December 13 (Box 23, Folder 72)
  - "Changing scenes in Rural Health": speech text, 1957 March 8 (Box 23, Folder 73)
  - "Address," American Drug Manufacturers Association: speech text, 1957 April 24 (Box 23, Folder 74)
  - "Public Health Research": speech text, 1957 July 17 (Box 23, Folder 75)
  - "Unanswered Public Health Problems," Journal of American Veterinary Medical Association: reprint, 1957 September 15 (Box 23, Folder 76)
  - "Postgraduate Education in Public Health": speech text, 1957 October 28 (Box 23, Folder 77)
  - "Public Health in a New World," Institute of Life Insurance: reprints, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 78)
  - Speeches: bound volume, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 79)
  - "Government's Role in Meeting Needs Rising from the Changing Scene," Digest of the Sixty-Second Annual Convention, National Congress of Parents and Teachers: speech text and related material, 1958 May 20 (Box 23, Folder 80)
  - "Nutrition and Chronic Disease Control," Nutrition Reviews: reprint, 1958 August (Box 24, Folder 81)
  - "A Decade of Health": speech text, 1958 October 29 (Box 24, Folder 82)
  - Speeches: bound volume, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 83)
  - "Church and Community United for Health and Welfare": speech text, 1959 January 29 (Box 24, Folder 84)
  - "Preparedness and Survival," Public Health Reports: reprint, 1959 January (Box 24, Folder 85)
  - "Physicians for Tomorrow," Bulletin, American College of Surgeons: reprint, 1959 January-February (Box 24, Folder 86)
  - "Dentistry, Medicine and Public Health in a Time of Change": speech text, 1959 February 9 (Box 24, Folder 87)
  - "Public Health and Sanitation": speech text, 1959 March 3 (Box 24, Folder 88)
  - "Dedication of the Children's Hospital Variety Club Research Center": speech text, 1959 March 22 (Box 24, Folder 89)
  - "Responsibility of the Public Health Service for Indian Health": speech text, 1959 April 11 (Box 24, Folder 90)
  - "The Role of the Federal Government in Basic Research": speech text, 1959 April 17 (Box 24, Folder 91)
  - "The Twelfth World Health Assembly": report, 1959 May 12-29 (Box 24, Folder 92)
  - "Health Problems of the Modern, City": speech text, 1959 July 15 (Box 24, Folder 93)
  - Sanitation and Sanity--Health Problems of the Modern Environments; speech text, 1959 July 27 (Box 24, Folder 94)
  - "Successful Planning for the Hospital System of the Future Will Call," Modern Hospital: reprint and speech text, 1959 July October (Box 24, Folder 95)
  - "Salute to the American Dental Association: A Century of Leadership": speech text, 1959 September 15 (Box 24, Folder 96)
  - "The Challenge of Cancer": speech text, 1959 September 30 (Box 24, Folder 97)
  - "Human Biological Drugs and Basic Drug Research," Food-Drug-Cosmetic Law Journal: tear sheet, 1959 October (Box 24, Folder 98)
  - "Address," Annual Meeting of the Association of American Medical Colleges: speech text, 1959 November 2 (Box 24, Folder 99)
  - "The Research Activities of the Public Health: Service": speed text, 1959 November 18 (Box 24, Folder 100)
  - "Smoking and Lung Cancer," Journal of the American Medical Association: reprint, 1959 November 28 (Box 24, Folder 101)
  - "Health as a Road to World Peace," Phi Kappa Phi Journal: reprint and correspondence, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 102)
  - "Opening Statement," Senate Subcommittee on Appropriations: text, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 103)
  - "The Challenge of Disability": speech text, 1960 January 11 (Box 24, Folder 104)
  - "Something New Has Been Added": speech text, 1960 February 11 (Box 24, Folder 105)
  - "Influenza Pandemic: Preparedness Plans for the Public Health Service": speech text, 1960 February 19 (Box 24, Folder 106)
  - "A Balanced Partnership for Health": speech text, 1960 March 15 (Box 24, Folder 107)
  - "Health in Human Communities of an Industrial Civilization," A.M.A. Archives of Industrial Health: reprint, 1960 March (Box 24, Folder 108)
  - "The Healthy Environment": speech text, 1960 April 6 (Box 24, Folder 109)
  - "Leaders for Our Medical Future": tear sheet, 1960 April 21 (Box 24, Folder 110)
  - "Leaders for Our Medical Future": speech text, 1960 April 22 (Box 24, Folder 111)
  - "Water Pollution Control and the National Health": speech text, 1960 May 26 (Box 25, Folder 112)
  - "Administrators of the Unforeseen": speech text, 1960 June 6 (Box 25, Folder 113)
  - Administrative Aspects of Occupational Health in the Americas": speech text, 1960 July 26 (Box 25, Folder 114)
  - "Changing Patterns of Medical Practice": speech text, 1960 August 4 (Box 25, Folder 115)
  - "The Role of the U.S. Government in Rehabilitation: Public Health Service": speech text, 1960 August 25 (Box 25, Folder 116)
  - Veterinary Science and Public Health—Partners in Progress: speech text, 1960 October 12 (Box 25, Folder 117)
  - "Federal Support of Medical Research": speech text, 1960 October 14 (Box 25, Folder 118)
  - "Remarks," 67th Annual Meeting, Association of Military Surgeons of the United States: text, 1960 October 31 (Box 25, Folder 119)
  - "Health as a World Resource": speech text, 1960 November 4 (Box 25, Folder 120)
  - "Radiation and Public Health": speech text, 1960 December 1 (Box 25, Folder 121)
  - "Governmental Problems in Environmental Health": speech text, 1960 December 7 (Box 25, Folder 122)
  - "Clean Water": speech text, 1960 December 12 (Box 25, Folder 123)
  - "Remarks," Joint Meeting of Health and Medical Care and Rehabilitation Committees, White House Conference on Aging: text, 1961 January 9 (Box 25, Folder 124)
  - "Beyond Your Hospital Walls": speech text, correspondence and background material, 1961 January-December (Box 25, Folder 125)
  - "The Fourteenth World Health Assembly": report and correspondence, 1961 February 7-24 (Box 25, Folder 126)
  - "Application of Knowledge": correspondence, notes and related material, 1961 March-Dec, 1962 Feb, undated (Box 25, Folder 127)
  - "Opportunities and Responsibilities of Teaching and Research in the Health Sciences": speech drafts, correspondence and background material, 1961 June-September (Box 25, Folder 128)
  - "The Social Obligations of Medicine": speech text, correspondence and program, 1961 July-September (Box 25, Folder 129)
  - "Important Implications of the Public Health Survey": notes, correspondence and program, 1961 August-October (Box 25, Folder 130)
  - "World Health—A Road to Peace," Journal of The American Dietetic Association: reprint, speech notes and related material, 1961 August-Oct, 1962 March (Box 25, Folder 131)
  - "The Health Sciences, A Common Bond Among All Nations": notes, speech text and correspondence, 1961 August-Nov, 1962 March (Box 25, Folder 132)
  - "The Changes Ahead for the Health Professions": speech summary, notes and correspondence, 1961 September-Dec, 1962 February-March (Box 25, Folder 133)
  - "World Health Problems": notes, correspondence and program, 1961 Oct, 1962 January-February (Box 25, Folder 134)
  - "Changes in Health and Medical Care Needs and Their Effect on Health Needs of Communities": speech text, notes and correspondence, 1961 November-1962 July (Box 25, Folder 135)
  - International Medicine—Path to World Progress, Military Medicine: reprint and speech drafts, 1961 Nov, 1962 January-February (Box 25, Folder 136)
  - "Conserving Human Resources": speech drafts, correspondence and related material, 1962 January-May (Box 25, Folder 137)
  - "Opportunities and Responsibilities for Cooperation in Medical Research": speech text, correspondence and related material, 1962 February-April (Box 25, Folder 138)
  - "The Hospital in the Changing Patterns of Health Care": speech text, notes and correspondence, 1962 February-Jul, 1963 (Box 25, Folder 139)
  - World Health—A Road to Peace, Journal of the American Dietetic Association: reprint, 1962 March (Box 25, Folder 140)
  - "Responsibilities and Challenges of Change": speech text, correspondence and program, 1962 April-November (Box 25, Folder 141)
  - "Changes in Health and Medical Care Needs and Their Effect": speech text, 1962 June 25 (Box 25, Folder 142)
  - "Remarks," 3rd National Conference on Health Careers: text, correspondence and related material, 1962 August-Oct, 1963 February (Box 25, Folder 143)
  - "Changing Patterns of Health Care": speech text and correspondence, 1962 September-November (Box 26, Folder 144)
  - "Securing Accountability": speech drafts, correspondence and related material, 1962 September-December (Box 26, Folder 145)